Let's look again at the steps contained in the V-model.
我们再来学习一下 V 模型中包含的一些步骤
The V-model shows the entire safety life cycle,
V模型展示了整套安全生命周期
starting from the concept phase through
从理念阶段开始然后经过产品开发
their product development and ending in production.
阶段并在生产阶段终止
In general, a functional safety manager will
总体而言 一名功能安全工程师需要
need to coordinate and document the entire cycle.
对整个周期进行协调和记录
Ask yourself, is my product new or am I modifying an existing product?
扪心自问一下 究竟我的产品是前所未有的还是我仅仅是在改进一个已经存在的产品？
If you are designing a new product,
如果你在设计一个新的产品
you'll have to follow and document the entire safety lifecycle.
你必须对整个安全生命周期进行跟进和记录
If you are modifying a product that already exist,
如果你是在改进一个已经存在的产品
you might not have to implement all of the steps in the safety lifecycle.
那你大可不必在安全生命周期中使用所有的步骤
New functionality perhaps only impacts
新的功能可能只会影响
certain parts of the concept phase or product development phase,
理念阶段和生产开发阶段其中的一小部分
so you can tailor the safety lifecycle to include
所以你可以对安全生命周期进行裁剪使其只包含
only the parts impacted by the new functionality.
受新功能影响的部分
That way, you can reuse some of the work that has already been done.
通过这种方法 你可以重复使用之前工作取得的成果
Let's say, for example,
比如
that you are working on updating an automatic braking system that already exists.
你在对一个已经存在的自动刹车系统进行改进
Your company has decided to use
你的公司已经决定使用一种新的电子控制单元
a new electronic control unit with a faster, more powerful processor.
其处理器运算速度更快且性能更强的
However, the break system's functionality has not changed.
然而 这个刹车控制系统本身的功能没有改变
Your first step is to make sure the new ECU really would not affect the braking system.
首先你需要确定新的电子控制单元对刹车系统没有影响
If the new ECU has no effect,
如果确实没有影响的话
you might not have to change anything in the design.
你基本上对设计不用做任何修改
You could also reuse part of the original functional safety analysis.
你可以重复使用之前功能安全分析的部分内容
However, you would still need to run tests to make sure
但是 你依然需要进行测试从而保证
the new electronic control unit integrates with the rest of the system.
新的电子控制单元和其余的系统集成良好
In the safety plan,
在安全计划中
you would need to discuss if the product being developed is new or just a modification.
你需要讨论正在开发的产品究竟是全新的还是仅仅只是对已有的修改
Then you tailor the safety lifecycle and
接下来对安全生命周期进行裁剪
discuss what sections of the V-model need to be included.
并讨论V模型中的哪一部分需要包含在其中
Tailoring the safety lifecycle allows you
对安全生命周期的裁剪过程使得你
to focus on the parts of the product that are new.
关注产品中较为新颖的一部分